Jamie Milhoan

Columbus, OH | 614-404-7660 | jlmilhoan@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/jamiemilhoan

- $\check{-}$ PROVEN TO POSSESS AN UNCOMMON BLEND OF HIGHLY ANALYTICAL SKILLS AND INTERPERSONAL STRENGTHS -
 - ACQUIRED FULL-STACK DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE WHILE COMPLETING INTENSIVE CODING BOOT CAMP -
 - DEEPENED TECHNICAL EXPERTISE THROUGH RESEARCH EXPERIENCE AND PROFESSIONAL TRAINING -

EDUCATION & TRAINING

We Can Code IT SOFTWARE ENGINEERING CERTIFICATE, 2017

Coursework at The Ohio State University
BS in Computer Science, Japanese, Digital Design, Minor in Mathematics

Coursework at The University of Nebraska Omaha BS in Bioinformatics, Computer Science

TECHNICAL INVENTORY

Java • C++ • Perl • Spring • Hibernate • JavaScript • Node.js • jQuery • HTML5 • CSS3 • Bootstrap • MVC • Responsive Design / Mobile • Structured Query Language (SQL) • Transactional Databases / MSSQL • Object Oriented • Source Control / Git Unix Environment • Maya • 3DS Max • AS400 • SV2

NOTABLE PROJECTS

https://github.com/jlcm2112/

- (1): Virtual Pets Project Created a console application for an interactive game-like virtual pet program in which the user selects from various menu tasks to care for their new pets. Technologies Used: Java, Maps, Inheritance, Interfaces, Object Oriented Programming
- (2): Node.js Simple Server Created a web server. Technologies Used: Javascript, Node.js
- (3): Cats Database Created a model which reads cats from a CRUD database and maps them to an interactive web page. Technologies Used: Java, Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Hibernate JPA With H2, Thymeleaf

EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS

Williams Sonoma, INC. Full Service Agent, 2016-2017

Escalated Client Services

Final contact for escalated client services issues

Safelite Auto Glass

Executive Service Agent, 2015-2016

Escalated Client Services

- Received 4 letters of commendation from the Vice President
- Worked in a dynamic, team-based environment
- Trained new employees

The Ohio State University
Student IT Specialist 2008-2010

Phone and In-Person Technical Support Specialist

Assisted students, faculty, and staff with various systems and technical support (hardware and software)

The University of Nebraska, Omaha Student Administrator 2006-2007

Student News Website and Systems Administrator

Worked with the student newspaper and faculty to manage content on the webpage and fix hardware issues